Shubham Shilvane

Front-End Developer

Passionate Frontend Developer with overall 4 years of experience and 3 years of experience in the Field of Front-End Web Development using angular framework. Hands on experience with the concepts and implementations of HTML5, CSS3, SASS, BootStrap4, JavaScript, AJAX, ES6, Flex and Angular, angular material. Eagerly expanding skills into Backend, dedicated to ongoing learning and staying abreast of industry trends for proactive Developers.

x shubhamshilvane1296@gmail.com

+919637014535

Hyderabad, India

vercel.com/shubhams-projects-bede0601

in linkedin.com/in/shubhamshilvane

github.com/Shubham-96k

PORTFOLIO:

Shubham - A Web Developer (shubham96k-portfolio-site.vercel.app)

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Frontend Angular Developer

OSSS Consulting services Pvt Ltd.

05/2022 - Present Nizamabad, India

Key roles and responsibilities :

- Led the front-end development for an E-commerce domain, ensuring a seamless and user-friendly experience. The major services include sales of electrical accessories liketransformers, solar panels, motors and batteries.
- Created different modules, components using Angular Material, pipes and directives in Angular as per business requirements.
- Implemented responsive web design techniques to ensure that the e-commerce website functions well across various devices and screen sizes, providing a consistent user experience on desktops, tablets, and smartphones.
- Implementation of different types of Quotation forms using reactive forms in Angular and TD form for Login and Signup Component.
- Optimized the frontend performance by applying best practices such as code splitting, lazy loading, and caching.
- Monitor and analyze website performance metrics (e.g., page load time, time to interact) to identify and address
 performance bottlenecks Overcame data integration challenges in the user module implementing a custom API,
 ensuring accurate and up-to-date information to users.

Frontend Developer (XPORIENCE)

OSSS Consulting services Pvt Ltd.

05/2021 - 05/2022

Nizamabad, India

Key roles and responsibilities :

- Converted PSD into responsive HTML using Bootstrap 3.
- Created interactions using JavaScript/jQuery.
- Used ¡Query Plugins.
- Fixing issues raised by team.
- Responsive website for browser & environmental compatibility on every devices.

Application Support Engineer

OSSS Consulting services Pvt Ltd.

05/2020 - 05/2021 Nizamabad, India

Key roles and responsibilities:

- Coordinated with Level 1 technical support specialists to take over calls outside their level of support.
- Assisted customers with more difficult technical issues requiring a greater level of personalized care and in greater length.
- diagnose and troubleshoot software and hardware problems and help our clients install applications and programs.
- Escalated support desk tickets to Level 3 in the most crucial circumstances.
- On boarded and trained all incoming junior tech support specialists.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Contributed Ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements in the angular project received positive feedback from users, leading to 15% increase in user engagement.
- Received a lot of appreciation from the team for quick learning and implementation.
- Received a lot of appreciation from the client for smooth delivery of the project.

SKILLS :	Angular 10		Angular Material		ypeScript	Java	JavaScript, ES6		CSS3	
	SASS	HTML5	Bootstra	ap(3&4)	AJAX	NGBo	otstrap	FLEX		
	RXJS	jQuery	NPM	GIT/GITHUB RWD			ledia Quer	ueries		
TOOLS:	Visual studio Code Vercel Postman Firebase Jira jQuery-Plugins									
	Augury Chrome Developer Tool ANGULAR-CLI FontAwesome									

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree

SRTMU Nanded

06/2017 - 11/2020

Intermediate (11th & 12th)

Swami Vivekanand College

06/2015 - 06/2017

Courses:

MPC (Mathematics & Statistics, Physics & Chemistry)

LANGUAGES

Marathi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hind

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

Full Professional Proficiency